<?xml version="1.0"  encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<book>
<T-booktitle-image>
<Img href="images/logo.tif" />
</T-booktitle-image>
<Text-titlepage>
101 Amazing Recipes Plus Illustrated Tips
</Text-titlepage>
<Text-titlepage>
By
</Text-titlepage>
<Text-titlepage>
Amanda Or Awomanda?
</Text-titlepage>
<Text-titlepage>
<Img href="images/blueorangered logo bw.tif" />
</Text-titlepage>
<Text-titlepage>
Blue Orange Red Publishing
</Text-titlepage>
<Text-titlepage>
San Francisco, CA
</Text-titlepage>
<T-copyright>
COPYRIGHT © 2018 Blue Orange Red
</T-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
First published 2018
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
All rights reserved. No part of this book may be reproduced in any form or by any electronic or mechanical means, including information storage and retrieval systems, without permission in writing from the publisher, except by reviewers, who may quote brief passages in a review. 
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
ISBN-13: 978-1721053667 
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
ISBN-10: 1721053662
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
LCCN: zzzzzzzzzz
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
Editor: ZZZZZZZ
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
Art Direction: Blue Orange Red
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
Illustrations: Blue Orange Red
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
All photographs in this book © Blue Orange Red, except pages 1,2,3 © Depositphotos.com
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
Published in the United States of America by ZZZZZZZ
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
268 Bush St, #3042
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
San Francisco, CA 94104 USA
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
www.ZZZZZZ.com
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
Disclaimer:
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
Although the publisher and author of this book are big fans, neither the author nor ZZZZZZZZZ are associated with ZZZZZZZZ.
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
All content herein represents the author’s own experiences and opinions, and do not represent medical or health advice. The responsibility for the consequences of your actions, including your use or misuse of any suggestion or procedure described in this book lies not with the authors, publisher or distributors of this book. We recommend consulting with a licensed health professional before changing your diet or exercise. The author or the publisher does not assume any liability for the use of or inability to use any or all of the information contained in this book, nor does the author or publisher accept responsibility for any type of loss or damage that may be experienced by the user as the result of activities occurring from the use of any information in this book. Use the information responsibly and at your own risk.
</Text-copyright>
<Text-copyright>
The author reserves the right to make changes he or she deems required to future versions of the publication to maintain accuracy.
</Text-copyright>
<T-ChapNum>
Introduction
</T-ChapNum>
<T-ChapTitle>
Who This Book is For
</T-ChapTitle>
<normal>
If you have just purchased, or already own, the Oster Expressbake, then you need this book! Here’s why:
</normal>
<1-column-emph>
Get the most out of your Oster Expressbake! 
</1-column-emph>
<normal>
Illustrated instructions, a quick start guide, and beyond-the-manual tips and tricks will teach you how to get the most out of your Expressbake so that it becomes your family’s favorite kitchen appliance.
</normal>
<1-column-emph>
Get a quick start with “10 Minute Mastery.” 
</1-column-emph>
<normal>
Our illustrated “10 Minute Mastery” chapter will walk you through your first bread loaf in under 10 minutes, so you can quickly enjoy delicious hot homemade bread instead of spending all of your time reading instruction manuals.
</normal>
<1-column-emph>
Clear, illustrated instructions.
</1-column-emph>
<normal>
Will make using the Oster Breadmaker so simple you can start baking bread in minutes while avoiding beginner mistakes such as missed steps, wrong ingredients, soggy crust, etc.
</normal>
<1-column-emph>
Go beyond the instruction manual. 
</1-column-emph>
<normal>
Our Pro tips will have you making bread like the pro’s in no time. Learn the science behind the perfect loaf so that you can confidently make the best, most nutritious bread you’ve ever had. 
</normal>
<1-column-emph>
Independent, unbiased recommendations, workarounds and tips on settings, ingredients and processes.
</1-column-emph>
<normal>
To help you confidently make breads that are perfectly tailored to your family, while avoiding common mistakes. 
</normal>
<1-column-emph>
Tips to Save Money. 
</1-column-emph>
<normal>
We will also show you just how much money you can save by choosing the best ingredients. 
</normal>
<1-column-emph>
101 of the best recipes on the planet! 
</1-column-emph>
<normal>
All the recipes you will ever need will allow you to make the classic breads you are already familiar with, as well as fun and exciting breads which will give your family the variety they love. 
</normal>
<T-ChapNum>
2
</T-ChapNum>
<T-ChapTitle>
What you need to know about the Expressbake
</T-ChapTitle>
<1-column-flow>
What does it do? 
</1-column-flow>
<normal>
The Oster Expressbake is a latest-generation bread machine that takes all of the guesswork out of making bread — a mysterious art that goes back centuries — allowing you to make perfectly fluffy bread almost automatically. 
</normal>
<normal>
The brilliance of the Expressbake is that it does all of the work for you: from reminding you to add ingredients, to mixing and kneading. The Expressbake allows you to add your favorite ingredients and choose exactly how you want your bread to come out. Its simple settings even allow you to customize your bread to your tastes. 
</normal>
<normal>
Best of all, it performs the most time consuming and labor-intensive aspect of breadmaking: kneading. With the Expressbake you don’t have to spend time sweating over your dough because it does all of the kneading for you. Once it has finished preparing the perfect dough, it starts cooking. All you have to do is sit back and enjoy the aroma of freshly baking bread.
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
What does it NOT do?
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
Because of the size of the Expressbake you will not be able to make certain loaf shapes like baguettes and round country loaves. Additionally, the Expressbake is designed to allow bread dough to rise and bake. As a result, the Expressbake is not ideal for making flat bread or other types of non-leavened bread. You can use the Expressbake to blend your dough for these types of bread and then bake them in a conventional oven. 
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
Who is it good for?
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
The Expressbake is perfect for families that use a lot of bread every week, because it makes large, 2-pound loaves that can easily fill the largest appetites. 
</normal>
<normal>
Another reason the Expressbake is perfect for families is because you can have the perfect bread for any situation. Adults often prefer the richness of darker crust, while children like light crusts, With the Oster Expressbake you can have either type of crust with the touch of a button. Its easy-to-use controls allow you to choose what type of bread you would prefer (basic, French, sweet, etc.) as well as the level of crust you would like. 
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
Who is it NOT good for?
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
Because the Oster Expressbake is designed to make large loaves, it is most likely not appropriate for people who only use a small amount of bread per week, as it may result in food waste. 
</normal>
<normal>
Because the Expressbake only makes one loaf at a time, it is also not appropriate for restaurants or bakeries who may need to make multiple loaves at once. 
</normal>
<normal>
Because it requires a large space in order to properly function, the Expressbake is not recommended for college students or individuals with limited kitchen space. 
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
Cautions
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
Because the Oster Expressbake has a powerful motor to ensure perfectly blended dough, the machine should always be placed on a firm flat surface. To prevent the unit from moving during mixing, we also recommend that you place a kitchen towel under the unit to help keep it firmly in place. 
</normal>
<normal>
The combination of the machine’s powerful motor with an automatic kneading function means children should ALWAYS be supervised when helping out. The turning kneading blade produces a perfectly even dough, but you need to make sure children do not put their hands in the machine while the kneading function is activated.
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
What are its Health Benefits? 
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
Many people are concerned about the role that carbohydrates play in weight gain and diabetes, and rightly so. Unfortunately, that means sometimes avoiding things like bread. But by making your own bread, that doesn’t have to be the case. While commercial bread may be packed with extra sugar, the bread you make at home in your Oster Expressbake can be so much healthier while still being delicious. From limiting added sugar, to using protein boosting sourdough starter, to adding healthy nuts and whole grains, you can make bread that is packed with nutrition and flavor. And best of all, you can make bread packed with real, wholesome ingredients, instead of sugars and chemicals. 
</normal>
<1-column-image>
<Img href="images/Depositphotos_118569690_xl-2015.tif" />
</1-column-image>
<Heading1>
Sidebars
</Heading1>
<normal>
A brief History. 
</normal>
<normal>
Bread is the most common food in the world because it contains vital nutrition and can be made with a wide variety of different ingredients. Basically, wherever you live, you can find ingredients to make bread. Because of this, humans have been making bread for around 30,000 years from different ingredients. 
</normal>
<normal>
Before we figured out how to make leavened bread, flatbreads were common in many parts of the world. A little over 2000 years ago, bakers in the Middle East figured out that by adding yeast, a natural leavener, they could make fluffy loaves which allowed their ingredients to go further. 
</normal>
<normal>
Better Than Sliced Bread. 
</normal>
<normal>
For many years, bread was sold in whole, unsliced loaves. Back in 1917 a jeweler named Otto Rohwedder invented a machine that automatically sliced a whole loaf of bread in seconds. It was the greatest thing since… well, sliced bread. Within two years of his invention, almost all bread sold in stores was pre-sliced. 
</normal>
<normal>
Modern Bread Machines.
</normal>
<normal>
The modern bread machine came along in 1986 when the company which would become Panasonic introduced the first machine which allowed people to make bread at home without doing nearly as much work. Over time, breadmakers became more compact and more functional. Today’s breadmaking machines, like the Oster Expressbake, are capable of making a much wider array of breads and do even more of the work. 
</normal>
<normal>
Modern bread machines are perfect for families looking to save some money and make breads that the whole family will love. You can customize the ingredients you use to ensure your bread is nutritious as well as delicious. And since a lot of commercial breads are packed with sugar and hard to pronounce chemicals, you can use your breadmaker to bake loaves that are healthier, just like when people started making bread thousands of years ago. 
</normal>
<T-ChapNum>
3
</T-ChapNum>
<T-ChapTitle>
How to use the Oster Expressbake
</T-ChapTitle>
<1-column-flow>
Setting up the Oster Expressbake
</1-column-flow>
<normal>
Remove your Oster Expressbake from its box and place on a flat surface, ideally a firm countertop with enough overhead clearance to easily open the top all the way. At this point, leave the Expressbake unplugged. 
</normal>
<normal>
Open the top of the Expressbake and remove the baking pan by holding the handle and pulling straight up. Make sure to gently wash the baking pan before using the first time. 
</normal>
<normal>
Attach the kneading blade to the baking pan and make sure it is firmly in place. The kneading blade isn’t sharp, but it will become hot during the baking process so be careful when handling it right after baking. 
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
Learning the controls
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
Select button
</normal>
<normal>
This button allows you to choose what kind of bread you want to make. Choose from: Basic, French, Sweet, Expressbake 58, Expressbake 80, Whole Wheat, or Dough/Pasta. Continue pressing the Select button to scroll through the options.
</normal>
<normal>
Crust Color button 
</normal>
<normal>
Your Expressbake allows you to choose from three different crust color options: (L) Light, (P) Medium, and (H) Dark. Continue to press this button to scroll through the darkness options. 
</normal>
<normal>
Display 
</normal>
<normal>
The LCD display allows you to see your current baking settings. You can see the type of bread you are making, the color setting, as well as the time remaining in the baking cycle. 
</normal>
<normal>
Timer Set 
</normal>
<normal>
If you don’t want to make your bread immediately, you can adjust the amount of time until the Expressbake begins kneading/baking. 
</normal>
<normal>
Start/Stop
</normal>
<normal>
If you want to make bread right away, pressing this will begin the baking process.
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
The Baking Process
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
Because breadmaking is a complicated scientific process, it’s important to understand what your Oster Expressbake is doing during the baking process. This will allow you to make loaves that turn out perfectly every time you bake. 
</normal>
<normal>
Mixing Yeast. 
</normal>
<normal>
As soon as you add yeast to your other ingredients, the process begins. Yeast is actually a living organism which occurs naturally all over the world (it’s even in the air!) When the ingredients are mixed, the yeast begins releasing carbon dioxide which is what allows bread to rise and form bubbles. 
</normal>
<normal>
Kneading. 
</normal>
<normal>
Your Oster Expressbake doesn’t just bake bread, it also does the hard work by kneading the dough as well. This part of the process used to take time and a lot of effort, but luckily, your Expressbake makes this step as easy as pressing the Start button. Once the kneading begins, the Expressbake will begin combining all of the ingredients in an even manner. In order to get evenly baked bread, the ingredients need to be evenly incorporated. This step is also important in forming gluten, which is the protein that makes break chewy and fluffy. 
</normal>
<normal>
Rising. 
</normal>
<normal>
Once the kneading is finished, your Oster Expressbake will allow the dough to rise for the appropriate amount of time. During this time, the yeast will have an opportunity to create more bubbles which will then allow the bread to rise to its proper height when baked. Because it is hard to know just how long to allow your dough to rise, the Expressbake is programmed to know exactly how much rising will produce a perfect loaf. 
</normal>
<normal>
Baking. 
</normal>
<normal>
After the dough has had enough time to rise, the baking process automatically begins, and the Oster Express bake will bake the bread for the optimal amount of time, depending on what kind of bread you are making, and your individual preferences. 
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
Workarounds
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
One of the challenges people often face when using any automatic bread machine, is that the unit will often start to “walk” during the kneading process. This is because breadmakers have a motor which does the time-consuming work of combining the ingredients. As a result, the motor may cause your breadmaker to move depending on your counter top. To keep your Expressbake in place, try placing a medium sized kitchen towel under the machine. This should keep your Expressbake in place and keep your counter tops in good shape.
</normal>
<normal>
You may find that after making a loaf of bread, your Oster Expressbake displays the signal H:HH when you are trying to make another loaf of bread. Since the Expressbake needs to be at an optimal temperature to properly knead and bake, you will need to allow your Expressbake to cool for about 15 minutes before making another loaf. 
</normal>
<normal>
If your Expressbake displays the code L:LL it means you are trying to make bread in a room that is too cold. The science of breadmaking relies on carefully controlling temperature, and while your Expressbake is able to control for many factors, it still needs to be in a room which is over 60F in order to properly function. 
</normal>
<normal>
When the display shows the code E:EE it means you are trying to use the Expressbake in a room which is too warm for the machine to function. If the room is too warm the yeast will not allow the bread to properly rise. 
</normal>
<T-ChapNum>
4
</T-ChapNum>
<T-ChapTitle>
10 Minute Mastery
</T-ChapTitle>
<1-column-flow>
10 Minutes to Mastery
</1-column-flow>
<normal>
The goal of “10 Minute Mastery” is to walk you through making your first loaf, so you “learn by doing” in under 10 minutes. Once you’ve had a chance to get familiar with baking a basic loaf, you can begin experimenting with the many other features of the Oster Expressbake.
</normal>
<normal>
Let’s get started on your first loaf!
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
Overview.
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
The Oster Expressbake’s “Expressbake” function takes all of the guesswork out of the baking process so you don’t have to worry about choosing a type of bread or color setting. Let’s start by making a simple white bread. This loaf uses the simplest ingredients and the most basic settings on your Expressbake, yet results in a mouthwateringly delicious, fresh-baked bread loaf that will make your family come running!
</normal>
<1-column-emph>
Collect These Ingredients:
</1-column-emph>
<ListBullet2>
1-1/8 cup water
</ListBullet2>
<ListBullet2>
2 Tbsp oil (vegetable or olive)
</ListBullet2>
<ListBullet2>
2 Tbsp sugar
</ListBullet2>
<ListBullet2>
1 tspn salt
</ListBullet2>
<ListBullet2>
3 cups bread flower
</ListBullet2>
<ListBullet2>
4/12 tspns quick rise yeast
</ListBullet2>
<1-column-emph>
Collect These Tools:
</1-column-emph>
<ListBullet2>
Measuring cup
</ListBullet2>
<ListBullet2>
Tablespoon
</ListBullet2>
<ListBullet2>
Teaspoon
</ListBullet2>
<ListBullet2>
Thermometer
</ListBullet2>
<ListBullet2>
Your Oster Expressbake
</ListBullet2>
<ListBullet2>
Cooling rack (or a place to place the finished loaf to cool)
</ListBullet2>
<1-column-emph>
Follow These Steps:
</1-column-emph>
<ListNumber2>
Simply measure 1 cup plus 2 tablespoons of water between 115F and 125F. Pour the water into the baking pan.
</ListNumber2>
<ListNumber2>
Add 2 tablespoons of oil to the water.
</ListNumber2>
<ListNumber2>
Add 2 tablespoons of sugar, 1 teaspoon of salt, 3 cups of bread flour. (Bread flour is different from all-purpose flour), and 4 1/2 teaspoons quick rise yeast. 
</ListNumber2>
<ListNumber2>
Place the baking pan into the Expressbake and press the Select button until you reach the Expressbake 58 setting. 
</ListNumber2>
<ListNumber2>
Press the Start/Stop button and your Oster Expressbake will begin kneading and baking bread. 
</ListNumber2>
<ListNumber2>
When the baking is finished, remove the baking pan from the machine and place upside down on a cooling rack. Tap the pan several times until the bread slides out. The non-stick coating on the baking pan will make this easy. 
</ListNumber2>
<ListNumber2>
Allow the bread to cool before slicing and enjoying your first loaf!
</ListNumber2>
<1-column-emph>
Congratulations!
</1-column-emph>
<normal>
You’ve just made your first loaf and learned the basics of how to use the Oster Expressbake. Time to celebrate! Give yourself a pat on the back and enjoy some extra butter (or whatever your love most) with fresh hot bread!
</normal>
<T-ChapNum>
5
</T-ChapNum>
<T-ChapTitle>
Pro Tips
</T-ChapTitle>
<1-column-flow>
Why water temperature matters
</1-column-flow>
<normal>
More than any other type of cooking, baking is a science and every detail matters. Your Oster Expressbake takes care of a lot of the science of baking bread, but there are still a few important factors under your control which will determine how successfully your bread turns out. The ingredient which determines how well your bread rises, and thus how well it turns out, is yeast. Because yeast is a living organism, it only does its job correctly under certain specific conditions. This is why water temperature is so important. If the water is too cold the yeast will be sluggish, and it won’t produce enough carbon dioxide. This will lead to loaves which don’t rise enough, and have a dense, doughy consistency. If your water is too warm, it will kill the yeast, and this often leads to even less rising. In order to get the best results, you will want to use a kitchen thermometer and make sure your water is between 115F and 125F. This is the perfect environment for the yeast to activate and do its job. Also, be sure to keep track of how old your yeast is. Because it is a living organism, it will eventually die and won’t be able to produce carbon dioxide.
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
Selecting the right kind of yeast
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
There are a bunch of different types of yeast out there and choosing the correct one can be a challenge. Yeast is a naturally occurring organism and it is the main ingredient used by breadmakers to make leavened breads. Prior to the discovery of yeast, all bread was flatbread. The best type of yeast to use for most applications with your Oster Expressbake is quick-rise yeast. This differs from traditional active dry yeast because it activates even faster and produces carbon dioxide at a faster rate. In general, most of the yeast you will use to make bread with your Expressbake will be dry yeast, however, there is one type of bread which gets its signature flavor from a wet type of yeast: sourdough. Sourdough is the oldest form of leavened bread and it is made using a wet “starter” rather than powdered yeast. You can make your own starter at home or purchase dry starter and hydrate it and feed it to keep it active. 
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
Bread flour vs. all-purpose flour
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
Just like there are different types of yeast, there are different types of flour which will produce different types of bread. In general, it is recommended to use bread flour when baking in your Oster Expressbake but depending on what type of loaf you want to make, this is not always the case. Bread flour is higher in protein than all-purpose flour, and as a result, bread made with bread flour has a higher gluten content. This will result in loaves which are chewier and denser than bread made with all-purpose flour. So, if you are trying to make a chewy French loaf,  bread flour is certainly the way to go, however, a classic white bread or brioche may be lighter and fluffier with all-purpose flour.
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
Weight vs. Volume
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
In most cooking, using volume as a measure is perfectly fine, however, because baking is more of an exact science, the best way to get perfect results is by using weight to measure your ingredients rather than volume. Over the years. bakers narrowed their measurements down to exact weights rather than volumes. However, because not everyone has easy access to scales, those weights were converted to volumes because more people had things like measuring spoons and cups handy. If you want to maximize your result, invest in a simple kitchen scale and follow the directions for weight rather than volume. If you do not want to use a kitchen scale, just be sure to use quality measuring utensils. Many cheaper measuring cups or spoons are not accurate, and this may negatively affect your final product. 
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
Master the moisture in your dough
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
In order to get the very best results when making bread, it is important to make sure your dough has the correct moisture content. This will affect how well the bread rises and how evenly it will be cooked. Traditionally, bakers have kneaded bread dough by hand and it was easy to keep track of how moist the dough was at any given time. Because your Oster Expressbake does all of the kneading for you, you won’t have as much contact with the dough, but that doesn’t mean that you can’t inspect it to make sure it has the proper moisture. During the kneading cycle, check the dough. If it is not holding together, add some flour until the consistency becomes more firm. You should also add a little flour if the dough feels sticky to the touch or if dough comes off on your fingers when you touch it. Conversely, if the dough feels flakey or floury to the touch, add a little water until it becomes smooth and elastic. Ideally, your dough should bounce back quickly when you poke it with a finger. 
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
Experimenting with flours
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
In addition to bread flour and all-purpose flour, you can also experiment with whole wheat flour which will result in a dense yet nutty flavor that is a great source of nutrition. By experimenting with different ratios of whole wheat to bread flour you can customize the perfect level of whole wheat from just a slight hint to a very dense and nutritious loaf. You can also buy rye flour which you can mix with either all purpose or bread flour for a hearty and tangy rye bread. The addition of a tablespoon of caraway seeds will give you a really authentic rye bread. Since there is such a wide variety of different flours on the market now you can experiment with adding many different types of flour. We recommend adding small amounts of nut flours like almond flour for an extra hint of flavor. 
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
Making pasta with your Expressbake
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
While you won’t be baking the pasta in the Expressbake, you can take advantage of its powerful motor to take a lot of the effort out of making fresh pasta. Because pasta dough needs extensive kneading to come out smooth and even, you can place all of your pasta dough ingredients (flour, eggs, salt, and a bit of olive oil) into the baking pan and use the dough/pasta function to effortlessly knead your dough to perfection. When it is finished kneading, remove the dough from the machine and wrap in plastic wrap. Place the dough in the refrigerator and allow to rest for about a half an hour. This will give the ingredients time to fully incorporate before you roll it and cut it. 
</normal>
<1-column-sub>
Adding ingredients to your bread
</1-column-sub>
<normal>
Once your Oster Expressbake has combined your bread ingredients you will have an opportunity to add different ingredients to your bread dough. Chopped nuts and dried fruit make an excellent addition and will impart an interesting flavor and texture to your bread. You can also try adding things like chopped olives and fresh herbs for earthy and delicious loaves that work wonderfully as a base for a sandwich or as a wholesome snack. Another fun way to add ingredients to your bread is by making sweet breads like cinnamon raisin or cranberry orange. Simply sprinkle in a bit of cinnamon mixed with sugar and a handful or raisins or add dried cranberries with a teaspoon of fresh orange zest. Once you get started using your Oster Expressbake you will find that the possibilities for amazing, healthy, and creative breads is nearly limitless!
</normal>
<T-ChapNum>
6
</T-ChapNum>
<T-ChapTitle>
Basic Breads
</T-ChapTitle>
<R-1p-Title>
The Easiest Bread Maker Bread 
</R-1p-Title>
<R-1p-Desc>
Baking fresh bread can be super-easy and fun right in the comfort of your kitchen. This easy to use recipe will have you baking like a pro in less time than traditional bread recipes. Great warm with butter or as sandwich bread, you’ll love this delicious recipe for your bread maker. 
</R-1p-Desc>
<R-1p-Servings>
Servings: 12	Prep Time: 10 min	Cook Time: 3 hours
</R-1p-Servings>
<R-1p-Sub>
Ingredients 
</R-1p-Sub>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 cup lukewarm water
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
⅓ cup lukewarm milk
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
3 tablespoons butter, unsalted
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
3 ¾ cups unbleached all-purpose flour
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
3 tablespoons sugar
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 ½ teaspoon salt
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 ½ teaspoon active dry yeast
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Sub>
Instructions
</R-1p-Sub>
<R-1p-Directions>
Add liquid ingredients to the bread pan. Measure and add dry ingredients (except yeast) to the bread pan. Use your fingers to form a well like hole in the flour where you will pour the yeast; yeast must never come into contact with a liquid when you are adding ingredients.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Carefully pour the yeast into the well.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Snap the baking pan into the bread maker and close the lid.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Press the “Menu Select” button to choose the Basic setting.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Press the “Loaf Size” button to choose 1 lb., 1.5 lb., or 2 lb.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Press the “Crust Color” button to choose light, medium, dark or rapid crust.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Press the “Start/Stop” button.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
When the loaf is done, remove the pan from the machine. After about 5 minutes, gently shake the pan to loosen the loaf and turn it out onto a rack to cool.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Store bread, well-wrapped, on the counter for 4 days, or freeze for up to 3 months.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Nutrition>
Nutritional Info: Calories: 183, Sodium: 316 mg, Dietary Fiber: 1.2 g, Fat: 3.3 g, Carbs: 33.3 g, Protein: 4.5 g.
</R-1p-Nutrition>
<R-1p-Title>
White Bread 
</R-1p-Title>
<R-1p-Desc>
Soft white bakery style bread is absolutely delicious and quick to whip up in your Oster Expressbake Bread Maker. You’ll love baking fresh loaves to serve as toast with breakfast or as the perfect complement to your favorite sandwich ingredients and condiments. 
</R-1p-Desc>
<R-1p-Servings>
Cook time: 3 hours | Servings: 16
</R-1p-Servings>
<R-1p-Sub>
Ingredients
</R-1p-Sub>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 cup warm water
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
2 tablespoons agave nectar 
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
¼ cup applesauce
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
3 cups bread flour
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 teaspoon salt
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
2 ¼ teaspoons rapid rise yeast
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Sub>
Instructions
</R-1p-Sub>
<R-1p-Directions>
Add liquid ingredients to the bread pan. Measure and add dry ingredients (except yeast) to the bread pan. Use your fingers to form a well like hole in the flour where you will pour the yeast; yeast must never come into contact with a liquid when you are adding ingredients.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Carefully pour the yeast into the well.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Snap the baking pan into the bread maker and close the lid.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Press the “Menu Select” button to choose the Basic setting.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Press the “Loaf Size” button to choose 1 lb., 1.5 lb., or 2 lb.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Press the “Crust Color” button to choose light, medium, dark or rapid crust.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Select basic or white bread setting for 1.5 lbs and press start. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Remove and allow to cool on a cooling rack when baked, before serving. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Nutrition>
Nutritional Info: Calories: 92, Sodium: 148 mg, Dietary Fiber: 0.9 g, Fat: 0.3 g, Carbs: 19.5 g, Protein: 2.6 g.
</R-1p-Nutrition>
<R-1p-Title>
Wheat Bread 
</R-1p-Title>
<R-1p-Desc>
Wheat bread is a delicious alternative to white and great for anyone on a diabetic or low-cholesterol diet. Baking this soft white bread alternative is just as easy as white bread, and can be enjoyed with soups, breakfast, and as a sandwich. 
</R-1p-Desc>
<R-1p-Servings>
Cook Time: 3 hours  | Servings: 32
</R-1p-Servings>
<R-1p-Sub>
Ingredients
</R-1p-Sub>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 ½ cups warm water 
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
½ cup honey 
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 tablespoon olive oil 
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 teaspoon sea salt 
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
3 cups wheat flour 
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 cup bread flour, unbleached
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
2 teaspoon active dry yeast
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Sub>
Instructions
</R-1p-Sub>
<R-1p-Directions>
Measure all of the ingredients into the bread pan in the order listed. Make a well in the flour and sprinkle the yeast into the well, choose dough setting and press start. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Remove the bread machine and punch it down, when the dough is done mixing and rising. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Shape it into a loaf. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Spray a 9 by 5-inch bread pan with non-stick cooking spray and place dough in pan. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Cover the dough with wax paper and allow it to rise until doubled; about one hour.  
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Bake at 400 Fahrenheit for 20 minutes. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Remove the bread from the oven and turn it out of the pan onto a cooling rack, and allow it to cool completely before slicing. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Nutrition>
Nutritional Info: Calories: 75, Sodium: 60 mg, Dietary Fiber: 0.5 g, Fat: 0.6 g, Carbs: 15.8 g, Protein: 1.8 g.
</R-1p-Nutrition>
<R-1p-Title>
100% Whole Wheat Bread 
</R-1p-Title>
<R-1p-Desc>
Whole Wheat Bread is 100% delicious and nutritious. This soft baked bread is also great for those who are clean eating or on a heart healthy diet. Serve it toasted with butter and jam for breakfast or alongside a delicious bowl of soup for a hearty meal. 
</R-1p-Desc>
<R-1p-Servings>
Cook time: 3 hours  Servings: 12 
</R-1p-Servings>
<R-1p-Sub>
Ingredients:
</R-1p-Sub>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 cup of water
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
2 tablespoons butter 
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 teaspoon of salt
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
3 cups 100% whole wheat flour
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
2 tablespoons dry milk
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 tablespoon sugar
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
2 teaspoons active dry yeast
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Sub>
Instructions 
</R-1p-Sub>
<R-1p-Directions>
Add the liquid ingredients to the bread maker. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Add the dry ingredients, except the yeast. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Make a well in the centre of the bread flour, and add the yeast. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Insert the pan into your Oster bread maker and secure the lid immediately.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Select Wheat bread setting, choose your preferred crust color and press START. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Nutrition>
Nutritional Info: Calories: 126, Sodium: 211 mg, Dietary Fiber: 3.8 g, Fat: 2.6 g, Carbs: 23.2 g, Protein: 4.5 g.
</R-1p-Nutrition>
<R-2p-Title>
Honey Wheat Bread 
</R-2p-Title>
<R-1p-Desc>
Sometimes you want a touch of sweet in your bread without the butter. This scrumptious recipe is just the way to go when you love wheat bread with a touch of honey. Serve it warm with butter and a drizzle of honey for a sweet Southern treat. 
</R-1p-Desc>
<R-1p-Servings>
Cook Time: 30 minutes Servings: 12 
</R-1p-Servings>
<R-1p-Sub>
Ingredients
</R-1p-Sub>
<R-1p-Sub>
Bread
</R-1p-Sub>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
4 ½ cups 100% whole wheat flour
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 ½ cups warm water
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
⅓ cup olive oil
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
⅓ cup honey
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
2 teaspoon salt
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 cup lukewarm water
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
⅓ cup lukewarm milk
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
3 tablespoons butter, unsalted
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
3 ¾ cups unbleached all-purpose flour
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
3 tablespoons sugar
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 ½ teaspoon salt
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 ½ teaspoon active dry yeast
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 tablespoon active dry yeast
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
2 tablespoons butter 
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 teaspoon of salt
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
3 cups 100% whole wheat flour
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
2 tablespoons dry milk
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 tablespoon sugar
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
2 teaspoons active dry yeast
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Sub>
Frosting
</R-1p-Sub>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
3 tablespoons sugar
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 ½ teaspoon salt
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 ½ teaspoon active dry yeast
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 tablespoon active dry yeast
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
2 tablespoons butter 
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 teaspoon of salt
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
3 cups 100% whole wheat flour
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
2 tablespoons dry milk
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
1 tablespoon sugar
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
2 teaspoons active dry yeast
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Sub>
Instructions
</R-1p-Sub>
<R-1p-Sub>
Bread
</R-1p-Sub>
<R-1p-Directions>
Add water to the Oster Expressbake. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Measure the oil first, then the honey in the same measuring cup: this will make the honey slip out of the measuring cup more easily.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Add salt, then gluten, and last flour.
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Make a small well in the flour and add the yeast. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Set to wheat bread, choose crust color, and press START. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Measure all of the ingredients into the bread pan in the order listed. Make a well in the flour and sprinkle the yeast into the well, choose dough setting and press start. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Remove the bread machine and punch it down, when the dough is done mixing and rising. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Shape it into a loaf. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Spray a 9 by 5-inch bread pan with non-stick cooking spray and place dough in pan. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Cover the dough with wax paper and allow it to rise until doubled; about one hour.  
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Bake at 400 Fahrenheit for 20 minutes. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Remove the bread from the oven and turn it out of the pan onto a cooling rack, and allow it to cool completely before slicing. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Ingredients>
Frosting
</R-1p-Ingredients>
<R-1p-Directions>
Measure all of the ingredients into the bread pan in the order listed. Make a well in the flour and sprinkle the yeast into the well, choose dough setting and press start. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Remove the bread machine and punch it down, when the dough is done mixing and rising. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Shape it into a loaf. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Spray a 9 by 5-inch bread pan with non-stick cooking spray and place dough in pan. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Cover the dough with wax paper and allow it to rise until doubled; about one hour.  
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Bake at 400 Fahrenheit for 20 minutes. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Directions>
Remove the bread from the oven and turn it out of the pan onto a cooling rack and allow it to cool completely before slicing. 
</R-1p-Directions>
<R-1p-Nutrition>
Nutritional Info: Calories: 232, Sodium: 392 mg, Dietary Fiber: 5.7 g, Fat: 6.5 g, Carbs: 40.8 g, Protein: 6.6 g.
</R-1p-Nutrition>
</book>