<?xml version="1.0"  encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<book>
<Chapter-Numbers>
1
</Chapter-Numbers>
<Heading1>
Why You Need This Book!
</Heading1>
<Image1>
<Img href="images/Yononas_Product.tif" />
</Image1>
<chapterpage>
Get the Most Out of Your Yonanas Frozen Treat Maker
</chapterpage>
<Body>
While the Yonanas Frozen Treat Maker comes with a guide, it doesn’t come with pro tips, 101 trendy recipes, the best fruit to use, or how to prep fruit for the best soft-serve experience using the Yonanas Frozen Treat Maker. I
</Body>
<Body>
f you’re looking for more ways to get the most out of your Yonanas experience, this book has everything you need and more when it comes to making the most out of your healthy lifestyle.
</Body>
<Heading3>
It Is the Only Book Written Specifically for The Hamilton Beach Food Steamer
</Heading3>
<Body>
To be honest, there are not a lot of people out there who appreciate the art of steaming as much as we do. This book takes steaming to another level by focusing specifically on the Hamilton Beach model and its many attributes. Not only is this model ripe with features, but it was also chosen because of the legacy of the Hamilton Beach name. By focusing on a single steamer there is no need to wonder if the recipes in this book will work with your steamer and will even tell you things about your Hamilton Beach steamer that you won’t find with its original literature. Imagine this book as a fun user manual that doubles as an amazing steamer cook book with delicious recipes sure to please the whole family. 
</Body>
<Heading3>
Learn How to Cook Delicious Meals and Snacks with Your Steamer
</Heading3>
<Body>
This book is not going to tell you how to throw some broccoli into a steamer; instead it is going to give you ideas and instructions how to cook full family-pleasing meals and out-of-this-world sides that you may have never thought of steaming before. This book will also teach you how to use your steamer to its maximum ability to make meals that you won’t believe came out of a food steamer. It unlocks a world of ideas that will change the way you look at a steamer.
</Body>
<Heading3>
Learn Surprising Pro Tips That Turn Your Steamer into a Gourmet Meal Maker
</Heading3>
<Body>
In this book, you will find the secrets to steaming a perfect meal. The ideas you will find in this book are not just rehashed ways of telling you how to steam food, these are real pro tips that will change the way you prepare and serve steamed foods. The best part is, that with the Hamilton Beach steamer you will be able to create many of these gourmet meals in a single machine and in record time. 
</Body>
<Heading3>
A Deeper Look into the Health Benefits of 
Steaming Food
</Heading3>
<Body>
Steaming your food is, hands down, one of the healthiest ways to cook foods. There are so many benefits to steaming foods both inside and outside of the foods and benefits change depending on the food that you are cooking. It is good to know just what these benefits are and how you can incorporate them into a healthy lifestyle. This book will delve a little deeper into these health benefits without getting scientific or boring.
</Body>
<Heading3>
Over 100 Mouth-Watering Recipes
</Heading3>
<Body>
Of course, the main benefit of this cook book is the crazy amount of delicious recipes that are packed inside. You will have access to recipes including vegetables, meats, rice, desserts, and more. The recipes inside are not just any recipes either, these are culinary delights that you won’t find just anywhere. The recipes alone are worth the cover price, plus you get all of this bonus information to accompany them. You may want to clear a spot on the counter because once you start you won’t be able to stop.
</Body>
<Heading3>
A Multiple Tier System for Cooking More Food at 
One Time
</Heading3>
<Body>
This machine has two bowls that stack on top of each other which allows you to cook whole meals at the same time. By cooking a protein in the bottom bowl and a side in the top bowl, you can effectively create an entire meal in a short amount of time. Multiple tiers also allow you to better control cook times by adding your second tier later in the cooking process.
</Body>
<Heading3>
It Steams Everything, No Question
</Heading3>
<Body>
Some steamers are not powerful enough to cook meats, but not the Hamilton Beach steamer. It cooks everything from pork to poultry, and even seafood. Of course, it steams rice and vegetables as well, and if you remove the divider that divides to the bowls you can steam large items like corn on the cob. This steamer is so amazing that you could even use it to cook eggs. Rest assured that no matter what you throw at this steamer it will be able to handle it. 
</Body>
<Heading3>
Cook Foods When You Want to with Delayed Starts and Keep Warm Finishes
</Heading3>
<Body>
One of the biggest challenges of cooking delicious and nutritious meals is getting them done on time. Life is hectic and sometimes it does not work to have to be as hands on with a meal. Hamilton Beach understands that, which is why they created this steamer with a delay timer that allows you to delay the start of your cooking and the setup couldn’t be simpler. You just put your foods in the bowl(s) and close the lid, press the arrows to set your delay time and leave it be. When your delay time expires your food will start steaming and when it is done the steamer will automatically switch to warm for an hour giving you plenty of time to plan around your meal. A few notions to consider are, your water level should always be at max when you delay cooking and NEVER use delayed cooking for raw fish, seafood, or meats.
</Body>
<Heading3>
Easy Controls with a Digital Screen
</Heading3>
<Body>
The digital screen is bright and easy to read. Three indicator lights let you know what mode the machine is on and the forth informs you if your water level is low. If you don’t want to rely on the water level warning, there is also a window that shows your water level. Apart from that, there is a power button and two arrows to control every function of your steamer. 
</Body>
<Heading3>
Takes Up Less Space for Easier Storage
</Heading3>
<Body>
I am not going to lie and say that this machine is small even when it is broken down, but it is smaller than many other brands. This is because of the unique nesting design of the bowls that allows you to pack all of the components together. It is not the prettiest looking appliance, but if you steam a lot you could probably leave this one on your countertop too. 
</Body>
<Heading3>
Hamilton Beach is a Trusted Name with 
Long-Lasting Appliances
</Heading3>
<Body>
Unlike many appliances today, the name Hamilton Beach still means something. There are people whose grandparents are still using the same Hamilton Beach appliances that they bought back in the 1970s. If an issue were to occur, this particular model is covered by a 5 year limited warranty and you can purchase replacement parts from the manufacturer’s website. The fact of the matter is that Hamilton Beach products are made with the same quality and care now as they always have been so the warranty will probably never be needed. 
</Body>
<Heading3>
Here is a new subtitle
</Heading3>
<Image2>
<Img href="images/Depositphotos_7509451_l-2015.tif" />
</Image2>
<Chapter-Numbers>
2
</Chapter-Numbers>
<Heading1>
Recipes
</Heading1>
<Heading4>
Fruity Frozen Yogurt
</Heading4>
<Recipe-Servings>
Servings: 5 | Prep Time: 5 minutes | Cook Time: 5 minutes
</Recipe-Servings>
<RecipeDescription>
Fresh frozen fruit is absolutely refreshing when you turn it into a delicious frozen yogurt. Enjoy this succulently sweet treat for dessert, as an afternoon snack or alongside gluten-free biscotti for a decadent healthy dessert.
</RecipeDescription>
<Heading5>
Ingredients:
</Heading5>
<Recipe-Ingredients>
3 frozen bananas, peeled
</Recipe-Ingredients>
<Recipe-Ingredients>
3 cups frozen mixed fruit
</Recipe-Ingredients>
<Recipe-Ingredients>
1⁄2 cup nonfat vanilla yogurt
</Recipe-Ingredients>
<Recipe-Ingredients>
1 tablespoon fresh lemon juice
</Recipe-Ingredients>
<Heading5>
Instructions:
</Heading5>
<Recipe-Directions>
Place a large mixing bowl under the Yonanas chute.
</Recipe-Directions>
<Recipe-Directions>
Push frozen bananas through the chute followed by the frozen mixed fruits.
</Recipe-Directions>
<Recipe-Directions>
Add yogurt and lemon juice to mixing bowl. 
</Recipe-Directions>
<Recipe-Directions>
Mix until smooth, then spoon into bowls.
</Recipe-Directions>
<Recipe-Directions>
Freeze leftovers in an airtight container.
</Recipe-Directions>
<Recipe-Nutrition>
Nutritional Info: Calories: 117, Sodium: 18 mg, Dietary Fiber: 3.6 g, Fat: 0.6 g, Carbs: 27.6 g, Protein: 2.2 g.
</Recipe-Nutrition>
<Heading4>
Vanilla Ice Cream
</Heading4>
<Recipe-Servings>
Servings: 5 | Prep Time: 5 minutes | Cook Time: 5 minutes
</Recipe-Servings>
<RecipeDescription>
Nothing beats a classic, like creamy vanilla soft-serve when it comes to the perfect dessert. Cool down with a creamy bowl, top it with fresh fruit or your favorite sugar-free sauce like chocolate, caramel, or strawberry for a super-sweet treat.
</RecipeDescription>
<Heading5>
Ingredients: 
</Heading5>
<Recipe-Ingredients>
6 frozen bananas, peeled
</Recipe-Ingredients>
<Recipe-Ingredients>
1/4 cup ultra-filtered 2% milk 
</Recipe-Ingredients>
<Recipe-Ingredients>
1/2 cup greek yogurt 
</Recipe-Ingredients>
<Recipe-Ingredients>
1 tablespoon honey
</Recipe-Ingredients>
<Recipe-Ingredients>
1/4 teaspoon pure vanilla extract 
</Recipe-Ingredients>
<Recipe-Ingredients>
1/2 teaspoon pink himalayan salt, crushed
</Recipe-Ingredients>
<Heading5>
Instructions: 
</Heading5>
<Recipe-Directions>
Place a large mixing bowl under the Yonanas chute.
</Recipe-Directions>
<Recipe-Directions>
Push frozen bananas through the chute.
</Recipe-Directions>
<Recipe-Directions>
Add honey, salt, milk, frozen yogurt and frozen vanilla extract.
</Recipe-Directions>
<Recipe-Directions>
Mix until smooth, then spoon into bowls.
</Recipe-Directions>
<Recipe-Directions>
Freeze leftovers in an airtight container.
</Recipe-Directions>
<Recipe-Nutrition>
Nutritional Info: Calories: 163, Sodium: 257 mg, Dietary Fiber: 3.7 g, Fat: 1.0 g, Carbs: 38.2 g, Protein: 3.3 g.
</Recipe-Nutrition>
</book>